<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vial on Ergohaven&#39;s journey</title>
    <link>https://blog.ergohaven.xyz/en-gb/tags/vial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vial on Ergohaven&#39;s journey</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.ergohaven.xyz/en-gb/tags/vial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Trackball mini guide</title>
      <link>https://blog.ergohaven.xyz/en-gb/posts/trackball_mini/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ergohaven.xyz/en-gb/posts/trackball_mini/</guid>
      
      <description>Preface The trackball itself, although it performs the same function of cursor control as a mouse, but the experience of using these two devices is completely different, and they are suitable for completely different tasks
Ergohaven Trackball Mini
The main advantages of a trackball over a mouse compactness - it will take up much less space on the table than a mouse, and even more so, such a small one, which was developed by the Ergohaven team; ergonomics - the position of the hand while spinning the ball, there is less strain on the wrist, and in general the control itself with the fingers seems more natural than the way we work with the mouse; The only downside I can note is that it is more difficult to accurately move the trackball over a long distance; in this case, I most often spin the ball with force, sending it floating freely, and here the predictability of where the cursor will stop is poor, so I have to move the cursor further.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Layer for apps</title>
      <link>https://blog.ergohaven.xyz/en-gb/posts/layer_for_apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ergohaven.xyz/en-gb/posts/layer_for_apps/</guid>
      
      <description>Introduction I’ve been using desktops in Windows for a long time, they’re very useful, I opened a work chat on one desktop, a browser on the second, an IDE on the third, etc., you can quickly switch without taking your hands off the keyboard.
At some point I had 6 active desktops, and to switch from 6 to 1 I had to press the hotkey 6 times&amp;hellip; and then back another 6.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All about Vial</title>
      <link>https://blog.ergohaven.xyz/en-gb/pages/docs/vial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ergohaven.xyz/en-gb/pages/docs/vial/</guid>
      
      <description>Vial is an open-source cross-platform GUI and a QMK fork for configuring your keyboard in real time.
The program let&amp;rsquo;s you customize your keyboard with an easy and intuitive interface without any knowledge about programming.
First use Download and install the latest version of the program or use the web version Connect your keyboard and it will be automatically detected Unlock the keyboard by clicking on the Security menu and then Unlock, and follow the instructions that will be displayed on the screen Change any key you want and it will be instantly remapped, customize various options to your liking Save the layout by clicking File &amp;gt; Save current layout (optional) Let&amp;rsquo;s now check what the main tabs do</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RuEn mode</title>
      <link>https://blog.ergohaven.xyz/en-gb/pages/docs/ruen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ergohaven.xyz/en-gb/pages/docs/ruen/</guid>
      
      <description>RuEn mode This mode is designed to
place punctuation marks in the same places for Russian and English languages, enter characters from the English layout when printing in Russian, switch the layout to English or Russian using separate keys. This works due to the fact that the keyboard remembers the current layout, and if you need to enter a character that is not in the Russian layout, it automatically switches the layout, and after entering the character, it returns the layout back.</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
