<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Ergohaven&#39;s journey</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en-gb/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Ergohaven&#39;s journey</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 16:51:45 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en-gb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hello World!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en-gb/posts/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 16:51:45 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en-gb/posts/hello-world/</guid>
      
      <description>New Year - new beginning We are glad to welcome you to our new platform - Ergohaven&amp;rsquo;s Journey.
Here you will find our blog, documentation, answers to frequently asked questions, as well as firmware and layouts for our keyboards.
Last year, it was decided to create a simple and convenient knowledge base specifically for our users, which will help in their * travel * in the world of ergonomic keyboards. We also decided to transfer a blog here due to ease of use when creating new article, and the most interesting thing is that this platform is completely open and placed on our Hithabe.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trackball mini guide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en-gb/posts/trackball_mini/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en-gb/posts/trackball_mini/</guid>
      
      <description>Preface The trackball itself, although it performs the same function of cursor control as a mouse, but the experience of using these two devices is completely different, and they are suitable for completely different tasks
Ergohaven Trackball Mini
The main advantages of a trackball over a mouse compactness - it will take up much less space on the table than a mouse, and even more so, such a small one, which was developed by the Ergohaven team; ergonomics - the position of the hand while spinning the ball, there is less strain on the wrist, and in general the control itself with the fingers seems more natural than the way we work with the mouse; The only downside I can note is that it is more difficult to accurately move the trackball over a long distance; in this case, I most often spin the ball with force, sending it floating freely, and here the predictability of where the cursor will stop is poor, so I have to move the cursor further.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Layer for apps</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en-gb/posts/layer_for_apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en-gb/posts/layer_for_apps/</guid>
      
      <description>Introduction I’ve been using desktops in Windows for a long time, they’re very useful, I opened a work chat on one desktop, a browser on the second, an IDE on the third, etc., you can quickly switch without taking your hands off the keyboard.
At some point I had 6 active desktops, and to switch from 6 to 1 I had to press the hotkey 6 times&amp;hellip; and then back another 6.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are switches and how to choose them correctly</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en-gb/posts/switches_guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en-gb/posts/switches_guide/</guid>
      
      <description>Introduction In this article I will describe general information about what switches are and will try to simplify the pain of choosing which to buy
First of all, what is it even, what does it look like? Switches are the mechanisms of each key on the keyboard; in the photo below they are highlighted with a red frame.
Switches are a key component of the keyboard, and their selection determines how the keys feel when pressed.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to learn to touch typing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en-gb/posts/touchtyping/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en-gb/posts/touchtyping/</guid>
      
      <description>Intro It&amp;rsquo;s no secret that our store sells keycaps without symbols, some customers are stunned and decide to get the standard keycaps with symbols elsewhere.
In this article, you will find out what is touch typing and why you should consider to switch to blank keycaps.
What is touch typing? Description from Wikipedia:
Touch typing (also called blind typing, or touch keyboarding) is a style of typing. Although the phrase refers to typing without using the sense of sight to find the keys—specifically, a touch typist will know their location on the keyboard through muscle memory—the term is often used to refer to a specific form of touch typing that involves placing the eight fingers in a horizontal row along the middle of the keyboard (the home row) and having them reach for specific other keys.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All about Vial</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en-gb/pages/docs/vial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en-gb/pages/docs/vial/</guid>
      
      <description>Vial is an open-source cross-platform GUI and a QMK fork for configuring your keyboard in real time.
The program let&amp;rsquo;s you customize your keyboard with an easy and intuitive interface without any knowledge about programming.
First use Download and install the latest version of the program or use the web version Connect your keyboard and it will be automatically detected Unlock the keyboard by clicking on the Security menu and then Unlock, and follow the instructions that will be displayed on the screen Change any key you want and it will be instantly remapped, customize various options to your liking Save the layout by clicking File &amp;gt; Save current layout (optional) Let&amp;rsquo;s now check what the main tabs do</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Documentation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en-gb/pages/docs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en-gb/pages/docs/</guid>
      
      <description>Hardware K:03 High Plains Drifter Imperial44 K:03 PRO K:02 M4CR0Pad Planeta Trackball Mini Velvet Software Vial RuEn mode </description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firmware</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en-gb/pages/firmware/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en-gb/pages/firmware/</guid>
      
      <description> Firmware Firmware update guide Source code Default layout User layouts K:03 v3 K:03 v3 K:03 PRO K:03 PRO HPD v2 HPD v2 Imperial44 Imperial44 Velvet v3 Velvet v3 Planeta Planeta M4CR0Pad M4CR0Pad </description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frequently asked questions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en-gb/pages/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en-gb/pages/faq/</guid>
      
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a beginner, what&amp;rsquo;s the best keyboard for me to start with? We recommend starting with 60% layout: K:03, HPD, Planeta.
You have different switches and keycaps to choose from, which is the best one for me to choose? The most common option is Brown switches (tactile) and XDA keycaps.
I need a low profile keyboard, do you have one? You can choose all of our keyboards with mid-profile switches and low-profile keycaps, the mid-profile switches are slightly taller than the low-profile ones, but still have a standard MX connector, making them interchangeable with standard switches, and you most likely won&amp;rsquo;t notice the difference in height.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High Plains Drifter v2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en-gb/pages/docs/hpd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en-gb/pages/docs/hpd/</guid>
      
      <description>Connection Before connecting the keyboard to the computer, make sure that the USB-C cable is firmly connected to the connectors on both halves When connecting the keyboard to the computer, make sure the USB-C cable is firmly inserted into the connector Customizing keyboard Please refer to the Vial guide
Caps Word function Press LShift and RShift simultaneously to activate Caps Word. This function allows you to type entire words in uppercase letters without holding down the Caps Lock key.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imperial44</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en-gb/pages/docs/imperial44/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en-gb/pages/docs/imperial44/</guid>
      
      <description>Connection Before connecting the keyboard to the computer, make sure that the USB-C cable is firmly connected to the connectors on both halves When connecting the keyboard to the computer, make sure the USB-C cable is firmly inserted into the connector Customizing keyboard Please refer to the Vial guide
Caps Word function Press LShift and RShift simultaneously to activate Caps Word. This function allows you to type entire words in uppercase letters without holding down the Caps Lock key.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>K:02</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en-gb/pages/docs/k02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en-gb/pages/docs/k02/</guid>
      
      <description>Connection Before connecting the keyboard to the computer, make sure that the USB-C cable is firmly connected to the connectors on both halves When connecting the keyboard to the computer, make sure the USB-C cable is firmly inserted into the connector Customizing keyboard Please refer to the Vial guide
Caps Word function Press LShift and RShift simultaneously to activate Caps Word. This function allows you to type entire words in uppercase letters without holding down the Caps Lock key.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>K:03</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en-gb/pages/docs/k03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en-gb/pages/docs/k03/</guid>
      
      <description>Connection Before connecting the keyboard to the computer, make sure that the USB-C cable is firmly connected to the connectors on both halves When connecting the keyboard to the computer, make sure the USB-C cable is firmly inserted into the connector Customizing keyboard Please refer to the Vial guide
Caps Word function Press LShift and RShift simultaneously to activate Caps Word. This function allows you to type entire words in uppercase letters without holding down the Caps Lock key.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>K:03 PRO</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en-gb/pages/docs/k03pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en-gb/pages/docs/k03pro/</guid>
      
      <description>Connection Before connecting the keyboard to the computer, make sure that the USB-C cable is firmly connected to the connectors on both halves When connecting the keyboard to the computer, make sure the USB-C cable is firmly inserted into the connector Customizing keyboard Please refer to the Vial guide
Caps Word function Press LShift and RShift simultaneously to activate Caps Word. This function allows you to type entire words in uppercase letters without holding down the Caps Lock key.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Layouts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en-gb/pages/layouts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en-gb/pages/layouts/</guid>
      
      <description>K:03 K:03 layout file for Vial K:03 PRO K:03 PRO layout file for Vial High Plains Drifter HPD layout file for Vial Imperial44 Imperial44 layout file for Vial Velvet v3 Velvet v3 layout file for Vial Planeta Planeta layout file for Vial Macropad M4CR0Pad layout file for Vial </description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M4CR0Pad</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en-gb/pages/docs/macropad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en-gb/pages/docs/macropad/</guid>
      
      <description>
Connection When connecting the macropad to the computer, make sure the USB-C cable is firmly inserted into the connector Customizing device Please refer to the Vial guide
Firmware update Preparation Download the latest firmware here Save your layout in the Vial program by clicking on the File menu, then Save current layout Installation Hold the top left key and connect the USB cable Wait until the controller enters bootloader mode and the storage folder opens Copy or drag the Uf2 file, after which the controller should instantly reboot and start working in normal mode Import the layout into the Vial program by clicking on the File menu, then Load saved layout </description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planeta</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en-gb/pages/docs/planeta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en-gb/pages/docs/planeta/</guid>
      
      <description>Connection When connecting the keyboard to the computer, make sure the USB-C cable is firmly inserted into the connector Customizing keyboard Please refer to the Vial guide
Caps Word function Press LShift and RShift simultaneously to activate Caps Word. This function allows you to type entire words in uppercase letters without holding down the Caps Lock key. Caps Word is automatically disabled at the end of a word
Win/Mac mode To switch the mode, you must press the Replacement Ctrl-Cmd for MacOS key on the third layer</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RuEn mode</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en-gb/pages/docs/ruen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en-gb/pages/docs/ruen/</guid>
      
      <description>RuEn mode This mode is designed to
place punctuation marks in the same places for Russian and English languages, enter characters from the English layout when printing in Russian, switch the layout to English or Russian using separate keys. This works due to the fact that the keyboard remembers the current layout, and if you need to enter a character that is not in the Russian layout, it automatically switches the layout, and after entering the character, it returns the layout back.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trackball Mini</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en-gb/pages/docs/tb-mini/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en-gb/pages/docs/tb-mini/</guid>
      
      <description>
Connection When connecting the keyboard to the computer, make sure the USB-C cable is firmly inserted into the connector Customizing device Please refer to the Vial guide
Firmware update Preparation Download the latest firmware here Save your layout in the Vial program by clicking on the &amp;ldquo;File&amp;rdquo; menu, then &amp;ldquo;Save current layout&amp;rdquo; Installation Press the top left key and connect USB Wait until the controller enters bootloader mode and the storage folder opens Copy or drag the Uf2 file, after which the controller should instantly reboot and start working as normal Import the layout into the Vial program by clicking on the &amp;ldquo;File&amp;rdquo; menu, then &amp;ldquo;Load saved layout&amp;rdquo; </description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Velvet</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en-gb/pages/docs/velvet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en-gb/pages/docs/velvet/</guid>
      
      <description>Connection Before connecting the keyboard to the computer, make sure that the USB-C cable is firmly connected to the connectors on both halves When connecting the keyboard to the computer, make sure the USB-C cable is firmly inserted into the connector Customizing keyboard Please refer to the Vial guide
Caps Word function Press LShift and RShift simultaneously to activate Caps Word. This function allows you to type entire words in uppercase letters without holding down the Caps Lock key.</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
